hello I'm your host David Bernard and my
guest today is Shireen khi VP of
Performance Marketing at derer Shireen
has been at dieser for almost a decade
working across multiple marketing
functions on the podcast I talk with
Shireen about why Performance Marketing
always hits a ceiling how to think about
and measure brand marketing and why
ignoring AB test results can sometimes
lead to better outcomes hey Sharina
thanks so much for joining me on the
podcast today hello David thank you so
much for receiving me I'm really really
glad to be here yeah really looking
forward to chatting I feel like I've
been saying this more and more recently
on the podcast and we actually have a
few episodes that will be released soon
where I say a lot of people in the
subscription app industry haven't heard
of dieser and don't realize what a big
app it is how long it's been around
there's kind of a lot of sleeper hits in
the subscription app industry that
aren't kind of like top of mind to folks
so I actually wanted to kick things off
there for our audience who might not be
as familiar with derer what is derer
kind of give me a brief overview of what
it does and maybe even a little bit of
history of the app yes these is um it's
a music streaming service it was founded
in
2007 by Daniel Mar basically a French
developer and businessman in Paris in
his mother's kitchen so it's really the
classic startup story at first it was
really a website of course in 207 and
then we we built an app for iOS and then
for Android so now we really cross
device we have very strong website and
also very performing apps today it's
available in handland in more countries
actually but our strongest Market is
really France it's our home market so
it's this has an interesting history
because it started with the downfall of
CD sales uh in music industry it was
launched uh at a time where everybody
downloaded MP3 basically it slowly
became an opportunity for the music
industry to monetize through monthly
subscription as you know so it's really
the core of our monetization model of
our direct monetization model it's
really monthly subscription but we are
not owner of our content so it means
that a lot of of these subscription
money goes to royalties to the labels
and the recording companies we also
monetize through ads but it's really
very marginal compared to what we to the
revenue we make from subscription and we
also developed a lot indirect
monetization through bundles with
Partners like Telos Hardware retailers
so we present in the US actually through
a deal with Sonos we are also present in
Latin America through a bundle with mer
lib which is used huge absolutely huge
there and we are we're partnering a lot
with st because that's really how we
actually started yeah it's fascinating
and Spotify had just started in 2006 so
dies are is really one of the early Pion
years in moving music to subscriptions
and moving music online as you said like
maybe a lot of folks listening to this
podcast any remember back in 2007 2006
and and even before that of pirating
mp3s and buying songs on iTunes and
stuff like that so yeah it it dies has
been around a long time and been a part
of this kind of like wave and while it's
not as well known as Spotify it's just
an incredible business yeah indeed uh
indeed it was at the heart of a big
industry shift actually and uh these
learned monthly subscription models uh
really on the go I remember when I
joined the it was in 2015 and I remember
that back then there was Major
discussions within the product team and
of course with with the marketing team
as well as to how far we should go into
frustrating users free users to get them
to pay because really at first the model
was a it was a freemium it was really
based on the on the idea that ads could
also support our business model but the
truth is that with ads alone we never be
profitable so once we realized that
there was a big question was okay what
do we do with all these free users who
are enjoying our product but not paying
not profitable and so we went very far
into uh shutting down all the features
and trying to frustrate a lot users it
was a it was a while ago and settled
them to Oh but you know in the end
grading the user experience the free
user experience actually doesn't uh
provide any uh good outcome because all
what you do is showing the your free
users that's uh well your product is
absolutely not satisfying on a free
basis and as I would just leave and use
another service premium is still
somewhat underrated especially now you
know a lot of subscription apps my own
included like I I I started using a hard
pay wall and forcing people to subscribe
to my weather app because similar to
dieser I have you know expenses with the
weather data and so there you there's
been a lot of talk the last few years of
subscription apps not offering freemium
or or like you said degrading the
experience but to become a really big
business alienating those free users
does kind of limit your pool and like
you said push people to other apps so it
it really depends on what kind of
business you're trying to build and how
you're trying to build it but it it's
interesting to hear that y'all did push
harder into subscriptions and then had
to dial it back I think that's kind of a
lesson for a lot of folks as I do think
about more strongly monetizing is making
sure that you do still have a valuable
enough freemium experience to keep those
users around exactly that's a very
subtile exercise where you have to show
your your value for money but that
doesn't mean that your free for the
tribs Amic yeah I mean even to this day
how do you and and dieser consider that
freeming experience as far as are ads
working I mean do do you monetize those
freemium users enough or is it kind of a
these subscriptions are kind of
subsidizing those free users with the
hope that over time more and more of
those free users will upgrade uh no we
actually reworked a lot of free
experience and the way we work with
advertisers to actually be profitable on
the free users we keep really focusing
on subscription to drive the majority of
our revenue and the way we see the
premium is more as a conversion tool
even though we did not crack it yet to
be honest it's tough yeah it is it is
we're actually doing the other way
around now is that we are opening more
and more our product and our user
experience to nond deser users we want
to encourage our users to share more
with and and really open the doors to
also users from other streaming service
yeah and then how does the Partnerships
you mentioned partnering with Telos and
partnering with other brands and stuff
how does that end up playing into that
premium experience are you able to to do
those Partnerships actually help kind of
subsidize the subscription to make it
more affordable or even free via those
Telos and others where the user
themselves aren't having to pay for that
more premium experience or how do you
work again I think you know a lot of
apps who aren't at dieser scale are
maybe starting to think like how do we
grow and how do we better monetize for
users how do we make it more affordable
or more accessible when we know just
broadly across the economy I mean not
everybody is going to pay for everything
how do these Partnerships play into that
well it's basically working on on a
bundle um principle so if I take we have
actually several types of deals what
we're doing when we work with a new
partner is that we do things ad do we
tailor it to their business objectives
and we look for the place where it match
so it's really about finding a a win-win
relationship and it's true that for our
partners mainly bringing music to their
clients to their customers it's bringing
a emotional connection it brings a lot
to their brand values it also helps them
connect better with uh with the younger
Target agents so that's uh that's really
uh what we're working on so for instance
one of our big partner is Merc lib in in
Latin America as I mentioned so Merc Li
is a it's a huge retailer in Latin
America who built a bundle with Disney
Plus for the video streaming and dieser
on the audio streaming parts so on the
user perspective yes of course the idea
of a bundle is indeed to have a better
price as a package and for us it's
really about retention again another
thing a lot of subscription apps I think
over time will find things like bundles
to be very effective because as you said
it's really fascinating looking at the
broadly across the subscription app
industry and something like Amazon Prime
you know Amazon under Prime now has
video streaming and music streaming and
like they've added more and more and
more to these bundles in order to kind
of provide that value and while it does
kind of lower maybe arpo in some cases
you're also kind of expanding the pool
of people who are then able to afford
the product so it kind of lowers the
ceiling but raises the floor I think and
what I meant by that with lowering the
ceiling and raising the floor is that
you know while you're average revenue
per user may go down in a bundle you're
raising the floor and that you're making
it more affordable to more people so
even though you have a lower Revenue per
user you're going to have more users
actually paying so it kind of raises
that floor of getting more people into
the app and paying even if you're not
making quite as much on an individual
basis as you would if they subscribe
directly that's really about the price
elasticity totally and for us partnering
means uh an extended reach obviously so
the mathematics are are positive for us
so the next part of that I wanted to
dive into is that you do compete with
some very large players in the market
you know I already brought up Amazon
Prime bundle where people can get music
now Amazon music is not not to disparage
Amazon but it is kind of not something
they seem to focus a lot on you know I
don't think a lot of people use that as
kind of their primary music streaming
but you know for folks who maybe can't
afford or don't want to pay for music
but it it seems like that's kind of a
smaller part of their bundle but then
you have apple music music you have
YouTube music you have Spotify music
dieser is competing globally against
some very big players and so what I
think would be interesting to kind of
dive into next is how you think as a
performance marketer about the balance
of brand marketing when you're going up
against such strong Brands but then also
kind of the Performance Marketing which
you're more focused on like how do you
think about that especially in light of
competing with these massive Brands
established brands in the space that's a
challenge I don't think there are many
app developers that are competing
against so big competitors when you
think that Spotify is actually the
smallest of all and the way we see
things obviously is that uh just as a pH
philosophy to start with we are the
Challenger we can do what others count
we don't have everyone focused at at us
and we're small and agile so uh in some
uh to some extents it's very challenging
indeed because we are maintaining the
same product as a sptify an apple or on
Amazon with maybe 20 times less
developers than them but we still keep
up the pace so of that we are super
super proud and we really think that
being uh small is actually it can be a
totally an asset an advantage and when
it comes with Partners actually about
Partners that's a big Advantage for us
because we can really allocate a lot of
resources to our partners because
partner is are like the weight a lot in
our Revenue so there would be a drop in
the ocean of spotify and actually
usually partners are looking to compete
also against the the big gaffa the giant
of the web so we know that that it's
it's an advantage on a day-to-day basis
it is indeed very challenging and not
always on the very positive side
especially uh when we we know that
Amazon Apple to name them they don't
really um like profitability is not an
objective for them so when we have
Amazon buying ourand Ed keywords on
Google they like they set the building
so high it's really hard for us to keep
it to Pace but we still uh we still do
and I I do believe that having to be
profitable and having strong constraint
actually make us more efficient and more
well smarter basically we are looking to
get profitable in uh in 2025 that's
really something that we are working on
as a company effort for quite some time
now our ambition is really to be to
become one of the first to be profitable
in the music industry I can imagine
that's pretty frustrating when you have
a massive company like Amazon buying
against your keywords which then makes
user acquisition even more challenging
but on a day-to-day basis can how do you
think about allocating resources to kind
of build the dieser brand but then also
do Performance Marketing in a way and as
you said as the competitor as a more
Nimble company you have to be more
efficient and effective so how do you
think about that balancing the
performance marketing side versus the
brand and and how do you kind of build
both for me Performance Marketing
doesn't go without the brand yes our
competitors are so big that we can see
it straight away but I think that's at
some point something that all apps
encounter when you focus purely and only
on Performance Marketing you hit very
quickly a ceiling a ceiling Beyond which
you cannot scale again so yes you will
catch some low H geek fruits you
activate two to three acquisition
Channel and you will see indeed user
coming in and they will be instantly
profitable and that's the beauty of
Performance Marketing but you won't go
very far with that and I really believe
that the days where this was working are
really over for the app industry because
it only worked in the app industry maybe
for the past 10 to 15 years and period
on any other industry you have to work
on your brand awareness because that's
the the beginning of the funnel and bu
the conversion campaigns all the
performance marketing that you do is at
the bottom of the funnel so for me you
cannot really perform in marketing if
you lose track of the funel so brand
marketing goes with Performance
Marketing it's just that so you Rew
workk your brand on the upper funnel and
yes it would be more challenging to
measure that's for sure and it will be
more challenging for you to convince
your top management that you need to do
it so this of course I get and that's I
mean uh it's it's a daily uh issues that
we all have to fix in Performance
Marketing but if you don't do that your
scaling up possibilities will be very
quickly very limited and I'm not even
talking about retention here because
obviously also to retain your users you
do need to have a strong uh a strong
brand awareness and a strong brand uh
preference because you know that at any
point your competitors will come to to
catch your users so for me it's indeed
very important to have a very good
balance between the two and that's to
something that I think that I'm Wonder
in at da I'm one of the best advocate
for brand marketing because I can like
we are on the first line on the on the
Forefront to see when our action lose
impact we cannot go further than what we
did because we focus too much on on the
very lower part of the F how do you
define the difference between
Performance Marketing and brand
marketing what would be some examples of
brand marketing that you do that you
consider brand versus performance so the
the main difference is really the the
objective and the kpi behind it so an
example of brand marketing activations
that we have is currently we have um
this massive TV and out of home campaign
live in France Al the campaign and other
the messaging is really about enforcing
the positioning of our brand it's not
talking about the price about uh trial
period it's not even encouraging you to
download the app it's more really about
what what it means to be a user of
dieser basically the vibe dieser is cool
yeah yeah no so beyond theel being cool
which is obviously one of our brand
value as you can imagine it's really
about making very clear to our user and
nonusers that for derer everything is
about music and everything is about
leaving the music we are not positioned
on all the audio we are very centered
around the music and all our branding um
marketing is really uh around this core
ID we also want to put back as user at
the really at the core of our of our
brand positioning so it's also all about
the user it's all about you these
activations we don't expect to have
immediate return on investment besides
the fact that we are not able to measure
that's not even the point really what we
are we are using brown trackers we are
using post tests so we really more on
the quantitative studies qualitative
studies to make sure that we do have a
positive impact on our brand image but
we know that we won't get immediate
Revenue out of it what we do though is
on Performance Marketing we are very
focused on amplifying everything that
the brand marketing team is doing to
make sure that we do Z know the final
little push the little pinch for users
to make sure that users who are ready to
convert will actually download our app
and convert into paying sub yeah and I
think that's what a lot of people maybe
underestimate about brand marketing is
that when people do have some level of
affinity or understanding of the brand
then when you do hit them with that
Performance Marketing that Performance
Marketing can be way more efficient and
effective because you've kind of like
warm them up as a lead and to kind of
backtrack a little bit I do think it's
interesting dieser scale you know you're
talking about Performance Marketing not
working anymore I think a lot of people
listening to podcast would be like wait
a minute you know our Performance
Marketing is working great but what
they'll find and kind of you alluded to
is that as they scale they're going to
find that Performance Marketing to
become less and less and less effective
and then as that happens that's where
the brand marketing does start to come
into play and you do have to be at a
certain size and have the the finances
to be able to spend in a way that isn't
going to affect the bottom line
immediately immeasurably but will then
make your Performance Marketing more
effective and so this discussion is
Maybe
you know for the smaller apps to be
thinking in the future this is how we
should be thinking about it and then for
the bigger apps that are already kind of
hitting these boundaries is that they
they really do need to figure out both
sides of the equation exactly at first
it will work at small scale it would be
uh well it would be super profitable and
you will be super happy but then it's
very short term so as soon as you have a
bigger competitor like we do have head
deser when you start fighting against an
Amazon for inst and Amazon is a very
good example what do you have left if
you don't have a brand what do you have
left to actually retain your user and to
keep acquiring new ones all you have is
emotional connection that you manage to
build with your brand and this is not
something that uh it's an actual
expertise to know how to position your
brand well Target your audience well
understand very well your users it's
really about Art and Science it's about
how you do a business while being uh
more understanding your users let's
start about the science part of that a
little bit though how do you measure you
kind of mentioned a little bit like
qualitative measurement and doing user
panels and things like that tell me a
little bit more about that like you
mentioned you do have kpis around brand
marketing so then why do we kind of talk
through both the measurement of the
performance marketing side of things and
the measurement of the brand marketing
side and kind of how you maintain both
at the same time to even on the brand
side making sure that you're not
overspending or being wasteful in that
spending and then how do you measure the
Performance Marketing piece and then
account for the brand Marketing in that
uh that's um one of my most favorite
topic because there's there's no black
and white uh answer to this question for
me we so everything became even more
complicated without the Privacy uh rules
so we we cannot track everything we want
anymore on the upside you cannot even
get anything before the last touch point
so when you think about that it leaves
you uh with pretty much no direct tools
to measure the impact of your branding
campaigns for me now measurement is
really about multiplying the source of
Truth you have to use different
methodologies different techniques to
measure different kpis and make sure
that they all align and they all point
to the same conclusions which you want
to be you're going in the in the right
direction basically so the way we do it
at DES that we do use many different
ways to measure on the brand marketing
side we are very much measuring the
trend of our consideration towards our
users uh through quantitative studies so
it means that every quarter every
semester we ask panel of of our audience
how they feel about does does theer Nose
music does theer understand me do I feel
close to theer and we especially focus
on the paid consideration part which is
basically am I considering paying for
theer so that's the what's actually
reliable on that is that we follow the
trend so maybe it does not measure super
precisely the actual level of pace
consideration but what we want to see is
an upward Trend that's also what we're
doing in terms of um of Performance
Marketing we follow the same pattern so
we do have last click attribution we are
working on a multi-touch attribution
model but it we we know that it will
somehow be biased because of the
different ways you track on web versus
app and as you know we are with cross
device so we do have lot more data on a
web Journey than on an app Journey we
also use incrementality testing so we do
as many increment incrementality tests
as possible to validate our assumptions
and as part of the incrementality test
we also try to figure out what is the
right level of investment on the digital
upper funel campaign so campaigns that
will drive instyles or campaigns that
will be much more about really reach and
frequency how do these impact our
performance campaign so these are Stu
that you can actually do very easily
with a conversion LIF study to um
through meta among other partners and we
have the mmm which is more of a
statistic model so it's not fully fully
functional at deser not fully satisfying
but this is still something that we we
are working on to keep the pace of um
what's really being done in the
measurement part at the moment so my
main goal actually my main focus is to
make sure that we always one step ahead
in terms of measurement for me
measurement is everything if you cannot
measure what you do all your efforts are
a waste you have no idea what you're
doing so yeah my next steps really on
the measurement side is to uh use the
results of incrementality tests to apply
some um scores into our mmm you know
once you you validated your assumptions
it's not super scientific but uh you can
work with these assumptions and end up
with a sort of a golden book where you
know exactly precisely what worked what
what doesn't work I think some of our
audience and when you said mm I was
expecting you to then say MMP mobile
measurement partner which I know a lot
of folks I think fewer folks will be
familiar with the idea of media mix
modeling can you explain that and then
is that all done inhouse or is there a
tool that you use for media mix modeling
yeah so media mix modeling is it goes
beyond tracking and attribution so mmps
for us like they are vital we could not
work without without MMP but as I
mentioned with privacy it's become very
limited so you can you can understand
your last touch point but you cannot
understand anything else media mix
modeling their objective is really to
help you understand the impact of um any
parameters to your business business so
it can also be um competitors
activations competitors offers but it's
mainly used indeed as make it obvious
it's really about your media mix so it
helps you measure the impact of offline
media such as TV out of home print and
it can also help you understand the
impact of your digital brand campaign
you know those that you do on YouTube
that nobody can really measure but we
all know that it works so to go beyond
attribution Medan mix modeling is really
about building a statistic model
comparing your spend versus your daily
or weekly uh incoming traffic yeah to
outline actually the the variations and
also to define a baseline but it's not
perfect uh because ideally for me in my
dream world an mmm would be able to tell
me what will happen if I stop investing
on anything we know we all know that yes
we do have a baseline but if we stop uh
investing on it a baseline with decrease
and yet really on mmm your your Baseline
is always flat it's not perfect you
cannot base all your decisions on an mmm
unfortunately that's why for me having
multiple source of Truth is key you
validate your assumptions again and
again the most informed decisions that
you can and is your mediax model all
done internally do you have a whole team
dedicated to that or is it a few people
in the kind of I imagine you kind have a
marketing engineering or a growth
engineering team is that mostly done
internally or are there any specific
tools that you use to help with that yes
the answer is um we we do everything
internally we have an amazing data
science team that spend times on
building those mmm and improving them we
work definitely super well with the data
team to improve it to me the I wouldn't
say that doing it in house is the best
setup for two reasons the first one is
that okay maybe those data scientist is
that you have internally maybe they
would be better working on your product
algorithm for instance on some some
maybe more product related missions and
the second uh second aspect is that what
I find maybe Laing a little bit is that
when you when you work with an external
company they theying so many different
company problematics and challenges and
uh they they are 100% open to what's
happening outside so they would be able
to feed you with the best solutions for
your for your own challenge so that's
still an open question we do it in house
that it's something that are work on for
2025 maybe about that the best setup
would be to have a hybrid of internal
and external because indeed internally
you will have all the essence all the
knowledge of what's happening in the
company and in your industry if you
Outsource a little bit of that you take
an external consultant to audit what
you're doing make some recommendation
coming from outside that might be a good
win you mentioned that part of the
challenge of mediax modeling is that you
don't necessarily get Precision in
understanding what changes will directly
impact the overall profitability of
spend but then you had mentioned before
that you layer on incrementality testing
so how do you use incrementality testing
in combination with medium mix modeling
to better kind of be able to understand
and predict which parts of your
marketing spend are working and which
parts are maybe less efficient so the
idea behind it and that's really
something that's done by companies like
L'Oreal it's my top of Mind company but
when I heard that they did that I was
like okay I absolutely need to do that
too so the the concept behind it is that
through in incrementality testing you
are able to calculate sort of a score
between what you actually see as direct
tracked data and what was more hidden
you know it's usually uh well it can be
on both ways maybe you do attribute more
directly to certain channels than what
they actually contribute like for
instance search to say it that's a very
basic example and maybe you do under
attribute to other channels that come
earlier in the funnel like social ads so
you can with incremented testing
estimate a score and use that score to
modify your uh statistic model your
media mix modeling so in your
incrementality testing are you
completely shutting off specific
channels or or like how do you actually
do the incrementality testing I think
really incrementality testing there at
level where you you need to be well
either you have an excellent agency to
Get You On Track you do lots and lots of
trainings but basically on an
incrementality testing there are
different methods depending on what you
want to check and with which partner so
one of them is a geolift and geolift is
really about shutting down some regions
and comparing them to not shut down
regions but the regions have to be
similar and there are tools on Google
that help you do that uh actually uh on
Google ads yeah and when you shut down
you can see you can calculate the
increment but there are many others ways
of uh doing incrementality testing like
as I mentioned conversion Le study brand
Le study where you have a controlled
group and an Expos group and you can
measure the Z uplift between the two
we're getting super in the weeds which
is a ton of fun because we don't always
get to do this on the podcast but I
think this going to be really helpful
for folks to be thinking about this and
again there aren't that many companies
at dieser scale doing this but the
companies that are on their way toward
dieser scale should be thinking about
these things and so I think it's super
fascinating and so just a couple more
questions on that front would you also
potentially switch off spefic specific
types so like maybe you don't actually
cut all YouTube ads but you withhold a
certain type of brand marketing and keep
the other brand marketing like what
other kind of ways do you use
incrementality testing to understand
those the performance so on brand
marketing you have to keep one thing in
mind brand marketing is not a short-term
impact so switching it on switching it
off if you expect to see a difference
between the two I don't believe in it
because you compared to um yeah for
instance you work with an ad Network and
you're not really sure that the ad
Network actually provides on the
conversion side then switching it off
and on you will see the impact you will
see it straight away because it's a
short-term Channel but whenever it's
longterm you have to be bit smarter than
just switching off and see what happens
Because the actual impact can happen
maybe next year or in two years you
don't know that it can be a very slow uh
decrease that's still also very
consistent and hard to reverse yeah my
last question there then is have there
been any especially
interesting results from the
incrementality testing so you know have
you done a test where you you know
removed a channel and wow like things
just drop like a rock or and the
opposite have there been channels where
you drop them off and like you just
don't see a difference at all any kind
of surprising results to the positive or
negative in some of your incrementality
testing actually it more it validated
more assumptions that we already had and
the surprise was to which extent it was
so um I would say that all the campaigns
that we do that are more a personel like
campaign that will um optimize based on
installs and not necessarily paying Subs
we knew that it had an impact that was
not so easy to measure on our
performance campaign but we did not
imagine how much so it's uh it really
confirmed the absolute necessity to keep
investing on upper funel campaigns even
though they won't have a short-term
impact what's really interesting with
incrementality testing is that it
actually validates the fact that all the
more conversion campaigns that you have
they only amplify what exists already
they don't create anything as such so so
that's again the the brand marketing
that's is Performance Marketing debate
but yeah Performance Marketing does only
amplify what has already started way
earlier in the funel yeah again just so
fascinating and fun to have somebody
like you on the podcast who works day in
day out having to make this work and
like you said you know these are pushing
toward profitability in 2025 these are
the steps that you take to make that
happen and so it's really great to get
this level of insight from you on how
that all works at the scale of dieser I
did want to shift gears and talk a
little bit about deer's approach to
experimentation and testing I think you
have a lot of interesting ideas there
one thing that I'm absolutely
fundamentally convinced of is that
nothing can be done in Performance
Marketing if you don't innovate if you
don't test everything that you can test
it's really and that's also why I really
love this job you have to be curious you
have to be daring and you have to not be
afraid of failing you only invest only
in the most secure campaigns with the
most secure audience and the most secure
your channels the whole relevance of
what you do will fall either in terms of
volume in terms of cost or in terms of
quality you will once again hit very
quickly a ceiling if you don't get out
of your comfort zone and go test some
stuff so that's why I also insist a lot
towards my team you know in France we
have culturally we are not raised to
test and fail we have this belief that
we need to succeed Straight Ahead like
at the first try and if we we not sure
that we succeed well better not try
so it's a lot of uh it's a lot of
Education to do I would say of company
values to infuse uh of same speech to
repeat to say no actually I will never
reproach anyone in my team to have fail
at something or what would be a problem
for me is people on try so what I'm what
I really expect from my team is that
they they do test a lot they have to be
very honest of the result of course and
not be afraid to say okay I tested that
and it failed and that's fine I mean uh
the main question is what are the
learnings learnings are so valuable that
yes it requires sometimes to sacrifice a
little bit of budget take a little bit
of risk because in the end what happens
when we do the math at the end of the
year and we look at everything we tried
all the biggest fail that we had versus
all the biggest wins what we see is that
wins always compensate for fails I think
that's also why we've been so successful
in the past years in Performance
Marketing I don't like to brag but we
did improve our LTV sack we doubled we
we more than doubled it in two years
time while scaling up on volumes at the
same time so pretty incredible and for
me there are of course many reasons and
it's also a company for it was also
because we collaborate very well with
other teams and we're all looking in the
same direction but the main factor that
helped us really scale while improving
our profitability is all the test that
we run and I'm really really very proud
of my team like the test stuff that I
would have never dared to test when I
was younger that's such a fascinating
topic from like a a leadership
perspective that as a team you're
spending a lot of money and a failed
test while not completely failed like if
you you know spent $50,000 in a new ad
campaign and and it performed half as
well as another ad campaign you're not
necessarily losing hundreds of thousands
of dollars because you're still getting
some level of performance but you are
losing money in that you could have
potentially put that budget behind
another ad that was performing or
another channel that was performing so
how do you instill that in a practical
level inside a team that you may
inefficiently spend a considerable
amount of money which I mean just as a
human you know it's hard to kind of
reconcile that and like go to work the
next day and be like oh man I just
wasted money and then how do you put
kind of guardrails against that as well
to where you know you aren't going to
lose hundreds and hundreds of thousands
of dollars in these experiments first of
all we do frame our test very well the
risk taking is actually quite limited if
you look at the big picture if you look
at the overall and that's really what I
encourage team to do is to look at the
overall sack as long as overall we are
profitable it's okay to test stuff and
indeed lose money so if you look at it
in an isolated way yes it's money we
would have loved to um spend it better
but rather than looking be and it's more
about looking uh ahead and get the
valuable learnings that would make the
next test actually overperform and
compensate for the loss and then how do
you incorporate gut feeling versus Raw
data into making some of these decisions
where maybe sometimes something appears
to be underperforming but you just feel
like it actually is the right thing to
do it's a being data driven as you can
have understand now is really key for me
so data is at the heart of everything
measurement is at the heart of
everything but at some points there are
stuff as a marketer that you did that
you know and when the data is not
showing is not showing it you should
definitely to me still listen to your G
feeling and do it anyway and see what
happens and I do have an ex excellent
example on that we had this homepage
last year our unlocked
homepage that's in terms of design in
terms of clarity uh nobody was really
satisfied with we developed two
alternative versions in which I think
all of us really believed that one of
these two will uh will overperform so we
would say more of a branding unlog
homepage with key messages around our
brand and our product and there was more
of a player looking like unlocked hom
page so a player but unlocked and
obviously with features that are very
limited and I encourage you to to
subscribe whenever you wanted to to
stream a song b basically so we we ABC
tested this Pages against each other and
none of the alternative versions one
against the control version and so yes
that's the moment I think that we all
agreed to listen to our ging which was
okay in all case the control version was
not satisfying to us it was not
conveying the messages that we wanted to
convey and it was not user friendly at
all so uh based on that we made the
decision to go live with um with a
branded version also we implemented it
we are we rolled it out now that we did
a few weeks after we see positive
results compared to to the old version
so uh that was one of the example where
we are actually right to listen to our
get feeling I think the key there is
User centricity it's like that you're
doing what is best for the user and I
think a lot of marketers and and we see
this broadly throughout the industry a
really kind of annoying example is the
gaming ads where the gaming ad is
completely fake the game itself doesn't
actually do anything that was you know
shown in the ad but those ads perform
but then people get into the game and
they're confused and and and that that's
just like a really blatant example of
not being user Centric where you can do
things in marketing that quote unquote
work or that you know the data shows
works but you're not to kind of the
point of this whole conversation you're
not building a a brand you know you're
not doing something that like makes the
users feel good about playing that game
even if it did actually convert better
than an ad that did show the actual game
so how do you think about that user
centricity and and how that kind of
permeates marketing and product and
throughout the entire user journey and
that was a perfect example of it is a
homepage that as a marketing team you
felt put the user at the core even if it
didn't immediately AB test better over
the L haul putting the user at the
Center did make a difference and it
showed over time which again that's
that's the hard part about being data
focused as well is that sometimes you're
fooled by your ab test because in
whatever specific timing or external
factors or other things that you can't
even account for in an AB test Led You
One Direction but it was actually the
wrong direction in the long term so how
do you think about that user centricity
and how to apply that and those gut
perspective to making those decisions
user censing is really Game Changer when
you shift your mindset as a company
towards listening to your users and uh
stop think that you you are part of the
users and that your personal opinion
does matter a lot because you use your
product and B that everything we come
from product features you know the
product Leed growth which does not take
into account really the needs of the
user for me the shift really means that
you equi yourself to listen to your user
ask them the right question and listen
to them all the time and actually kind
of delegates some of the decision making
good example is when we changed our logo
so before 2023 we had equalizer as a
logo it was our logo ever since our
creation so from
2007 until 2023 we had the equalizer as
a logo we knew that we needed to change
from different kind of of reasons but we
knew that we had this big problem of
brand attribution somehow logo didn't
seem to be recognized very well which is
surprising when you know that it was so
it it was there for like since forever
and so we decided to change it but we we
did not decide to change it just because
we we were convinced that it was needed
we decided to change it because we asked
our users we asked them to uh draw our
our current logo to see if they were
able to draw it we also tested our
existing logo against two alternate
versions and we were like this is not a
person opinion so we had this now our
logo is a purple heart so a big big
change really really really internally
it was a big change to go from a very
Tech equalizer to a purple heart which
is much more into the emotion connecting
emotions with our users so nobody really
believed that the Purple Heart would be
uh the winning version because it was so
disruptive and maybe looking more like a
dating app stuff like that but it
actually what came out of the studies
was that it was winning version and it
was a winning version by far and it was
a winning version on all Target audence
and to through all T and for me that's
the example of user centricity like we
listen to the users and uh and we
implemented we made decision based on it
and what we see really all our signals
is that uh it was the right decision to
make ever since I also believe strongly
that it really helped my performance
campaign to be again more profitable
while cleaning up so yeah user
Simplicity should be at the heart of any
marketing actually well I think that's a
fantastic place to wrap up this
conversation is that and and again I
think in a world of ab test this and
that and use every dark pattern you
possibly can to encourage people to
subscribe in the first couple of minutes
A lot of that works and sometimes you
you use some of those tactics to get to
the profitability level you need to get
to but in the long run what wins is
providing a really good experience had a
good feeling to the users so I think
it's a fantastic place to wrap up and
then even especially you know throughout
this entire conversation about brand and
performance and the and the combination
of the two the fact that listening to
users and being user Centric even so far
as changing your logo then actually
increased performance on Performance
Marketing is just fascinating so thank
you so much for all these insights
anything you wanted to share as we're
wrapping up we're going to include links
to your LinkedIn and uh I know dieser is
hiring so we're going to link to the job
page as well but anything else you
wanted to share as we're wrapping up
yeah we Rec covered everything thank you
very much for inviting me to your
podcast I mean um these are questions
that I'm always happy to uh to have a
followup on so I would be super happy to
connect with anyone interested in
measurement especially so we can share
experiences don't sleep on those uh the
job links Paris is an incredible City
and dieser is not remote right so so
pretty much everybody all the job
listings I saw were Paris specific so if
you if you work in uh mobile marketing
and want a cool job in a cool City go
check out the derer jobs page you're
just talking to for the last hour it
sounds like it's a fantastic place to
work and really doing some Cutting Edge
things and marketing and you know being
the underdog and kind of getting into
fight against the bigger players in the
space so I think it's a a really cool
company and uh a really cool opportunity
for folks yes definitely so if you want
to move in Paris these should definitely
be on the list of of companies you uh
you apply to we do have uh several jobs
opening at the moment and obviously
there will be many opportunities in the
future in the future at the moment we're
looking for a senior SEO manager by the
way so uh if you're interested you can
apply on on our desert jobs board and
also reach out directly to me voila
voila
and is so wonderful so all right thank
you so much Shena for joining me this is
a fascinating conversation thank you
David
thanks so much for listening if you have
a minute please leave a review in your
favorite podcast player you can also
stop by chat. sub club.com to join our
private community
[Music]